A Guide to the Preston-Radford Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #6353
Preston-Radford Papers 1744-1895
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
6353
ca. 1300 items
Mrs. William P. Moore
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift to the Library from Mrs. William P. Moore of Charlottesville, Virginia, on June 22, 1960.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of ca. 1300 items (4 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2 linear shelf feet), 1744-1895, chiefly correspondence, financial, land, legal, military correspondence and other records pertaining to four generations of the Preston and later, the Radford family.
The correspondence, 1763-1895, includes several letters from University of Virginia students (see folders for the years 1819 to 1828) mention: negotiation difficulties with a Mr. and Mrs. D. F. Carr, the reputation of "Mr. Jefferson" (1819 August 2) and the intention of General [John Hartwell] Cocke to "petition to cut a double moat, or construct some kind of barrier to prevent the students from visiting Charlottesville" (1828 June 1).
Land records, 1744-1810 & 1858, include surveyors' field notes and sketches as well as records of transactions involving large acreage of lands in Augusta and adjoining Virginia counties.
Financial records, 1745-1865, include estate settlements, receipts, promissory notes, bills and ledgers.
Military records, 1756-1766 & 1792, are concerned with Fort Miller and Fort George on the Virginia frontier in British North America. These mention "obligations of the country" to various individuals and accounts of provisions for Cherokee Indians. Morning report dated 1792 are also present.
Arrangement
The documents are arranged chronologically within the individual folders.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1763-1815; 5 folders (Box Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1816-1847; 5 folders (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1848-1895, n.d.; 4 folders (Box Box 3)
- Financial, 1745-1792; 2 folders (Box Box 3)
- Financial, 1794-1865, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Land Records: Surveys, 1744-1810, 1858, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Land Transactions, 1745-1818, 1845, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Legal, 1773-1843, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Lists, 1770, 1791, 1806-1816 (Box Box 3)
- Military Records (Financial and Personnel), 1756-1766, 1792, n.d. (Box Box 3)
- Miscellaneous, 1761-1795, 1820, 1846, 1885, n.d. (Box Box 3)